Inventaris van het archief van het Institute of Social Studies, 1952-2009
Nationaal Archief, Den Haag
- Taakuitoefening, C.
  - Onderwijs, C.1
    - Cursusaanbod, C.1.5
      - Academic Calenders, 640-674
        - 1993 - 1994, 659; 1 omslag
          Development. Law and Social Justice: a Special Teaching Programme on Human Rights, September 15-November 4, 1993 -General Information on Academic Programmes, 1993-1994 -Master of Arts 1993-1994 -+Specializations 1993-1994 -+Politics Alternative Development Strategies -+Agricultural and Rural Development -+Economics of Development -+Labour and Development -+Public Policy and Administration -+Regional Development Planning -+Woman and development -Diploma Programmes 1993-1994 -+Rural Policy and Project Planning -+International Relations and Development -+Population and Development -+International Law and Organization for Development -+Development Planning Techniques
        - 1994 - 1995, 660; 1 omslag
          Development. Law and Social Justice: a Special Teaching Programme on Human Rights, September 7-October 27, 1994 -General Information on Academic Programmes, 1994-1995 -Master of Arts 1994-1995 -+Politics Alternative Development Strategies -+Agricultural and Rural Development -+Economics of Development -+Public Policy and Administration -+Woman and Development -+Specializations 1994-1995 -Diploma Programmes 1994-1995 -+Rural Policy and Project Planning -+International Relations and Development -+Population and Development -+International Law and Organization for Development -+Local and Regional Development -+Development Planning Techniques -+Employment and Labour Studies -Development. Law and Social Justice: a Special Teaching Programme on Human Rights, 20 april-13 June 1995
        - 1995 - 1996, 661; 1 omslag
          General Information on Academic Programmes, 1995-1996 -Master of Arts 1995-1996 -+Employment and Labour Studies -+Local and Regional Development -+Woman and Development -+Public Policy and Administration -+Economics of Development -+Agricultural and Rural Development -+Politics Alternative Development Strategies -+Specializations -Diploma Programmes 1995-1996 -+Rural Policy and Project Planning -+Development Planning Techniques (With Computer Applications) -+International Law and Organization for Development -+International Relations and Development -
        - 1996 - 1997, 662; 1 omslag
          General Information on Academic Programmes, 1996-1997+ -Master of Arts 1996-1997+ -+Politics Alternative Development Strategies -+Agricultural and Rural Development -+Economics of Development -+Public Policy and Administration -+Woman and Development -+Employment and Labour Studies -+Local and Regional Development -+Specializations -Diploma Programmes 1996-1997 -+Rural Policy and Project Planning -+International Relations and Development -+International Law and Organization for Development -+Development Planning Techniques (With Computer Applications), -Development, Law and social Justice, 15 April-5 June 1997
        - 1997 - 1998, 663; 1 pak
          Master of Arts 1997-1998 -+Politics Alternative Development Strategies -+Agricultural and Rural Development -+Economics of Development -+Public Policy and Administration -+Woman and Development -+Employment and Labour Studies -+Local and Regional Development -+Population and Development -+Specializations -Diploma Programmes 1997-1998 -+Rural Policy and Project Planning -+International Relations and Development -+International Law and Organization for Development -+Development Planning Techniques (With Computer Applications), Development, Law and Social Justice, 4 March-22 April
        - 1998 - 1999, 664; 1 omslag
          Master of Arts in Development Studies, Academic Calendar, 1998-1999, 47th Academic Year -Diploma Programmes 1998-1999 -+Rural Policy and Project Planning -+International Relations and Development -+International Law and Organization for Development -+Development Planning Techniques (With Computer Applications), -Development, Law and Social Justice, 2 March-20 April 1999
        - 1999 - 2000, 665; 1 omslag
          Master of Arts in Development Studies, Academic Calendar, 1999-2000, 48th Academic Year -Diploma Programmes 1999-2000 -+Rural Policy and Project Planning -+International Relations and Development -+International Law and Organization for Development -+Development Planning Techniques (With Computer Applications), -Development, Law and social Justice, 1 Maart-19 April 2000
        - 2000 - 2001, 666; 1 omslag
          Master of Arts in Development Studies, Academic Calendar, 2000-2001, 49th Academic Year -Diploma Programmes 2000-2001 -+Rural Policy and Project Planning -+International Relations and Development -+International Law and Organization for Development -+Development Planning Techniques (With Computer Applications), -Development, Law and Social Justice, 21 May-6 July 2001
        - 2001 - 2002, 667; 1 pak
          Master of Arts in Development Studies, Academic Calendar, 2001-2002, 50th Academic Year -Postgraduate Diploma Programmes 2002 -+Postgraduate Diploma Programmes at ISS, January-July, 2002 -+Meeting New Demands, Postgraduate Diploma Programmes, 2002 -+Managing Rural Resources and Resource conflicts -+Development, Law and Social Justice -+Children and Development -+Effective Social Policies for Human Development -+Human Rights -+Universalising Social Security -+Modelling and Accounting for Sustainable Development -+Governance, Democratisation and Public Policy -+Globalisation and Development -+Policy Analysis Skills for Transition Economies -+International Law and Sustainable Development
        - 2002 - 2003, 668; 1 omslag
          Master of Arts in Development Studies, Academic Calendar, 2002-2003, 51st Academic Year -MSc Program in Development Economics, Calendar, 2002-2003 -Postgraduate Diploma Programmes 2003 -+Managing Rural Resources and Resource conflicts -+Children and Development -+Effective Social Policies for Human Development -+Human Rights -+Universalising Social Security -+Modelling and Accounting for Sustainable Development -+Governance, Democratisation and Public Policy -+Globalisation and Development -+Policy Analysis Skills for Transition Economies -+International Law and Sustainable Development -Special Graduate Programme on Development, Law and Social Justice, 2003
        - 2003 - 2004, 669; 1 omslag
          Master of Arts in Development Studies, Academic Calendar, 2003-2004 -Postgraduate Diploma Programmes 2004 -+Children and Development -+Effective Social Policies for Human Development -+Human Rights -+Universalising Socio-Economic Security for the Poor -+Policy Analysis Skills for Transition Economies -+Feminist Development Economics -Special Graduate Programme on Development, Law and Social Justice, 2004
        - 2004 - 2005, 670; 1 omslag
          bevat: Master of Arts in Development Studies, Academic Calendar, 04/05, 53rd Academic Year -Postgraduate Diploma Programmes 2005 -+Children, Youth and Development -+Effective Social Policies for Human Development -+Human Rights -+Universalising Socio-Economic Security for the Poor -+Modelling and Accounting for Sustainable Development -+Governance, Democratisation and Public Policy -+Policy Analysis Skills for Transition Economies -+Feminist Development Economics -+Globalisation and Labour Rights -Special Graduate Programme on Development, Law and Social Justice, 2005 -
        - 2005 - 2006, 671; 1 omslag
          bevat: Master of Arts in Development Studies, Academic Calendar, 2005-2006, 54th Academic Year -Postgraduate Diploma Programmes+2006 -+Children, Youth and Development -+Universalising Socio-Economic Security for the Poor -+Modelling and Accounting for Sustainable Development -+Governance, Democratization and Public Policy -Postgraduate Short Course on Gender and Economic Policy Analysis 2006
        - Master of Arts in Development Studies, Academic Calendar, 2006 - 2007, 55th Academic Year, 672; 1 omslag
        - 2007 - 2008, 673; 1 omslag
          bevat: Master of Arts in Development Studies, Academic Calendar, 2007-2008, 56th Academic Year -Diploma Programme in Governance, Democratisation and Public Policy 2008
        - Master of Arts in Development Studies, Academic Calendar, 2008 - 2009, 57th Academic Year, 674; 1 omslag
    - Samenwerking, C.1.6
      - Samenwerking met Nederlandse universiteiten en instellingen, C.1.6.1
        - Stukken betreffende de samenwerking met Nederlandse universiteiten en instellingen, 1998 - 2001; 675; 1 pak
        - Rijksuniversiteit te Utrecht, 1990-1993, 1997-2008; 676-677; 2 omslagen
          - 1990 - 1995, 676
          - 1997 - 2008, 677
        - Universiteit van Amsterdam, 1990 - 2000; 678; 1 omslag
        - Rijksuniversiteit Leiden, 1989 - 2000; 679; 1 omslag
        - Rijksuniversiteit Groningen, 1990 - 1993; 680; 1 omslag
        - Erasmusuniversiteit Rotterdam, 1989-1991, 2007-2008; 681; 1 omslag
        - Interuniversitair Centrum voor Studie en Documentatie van Latijns Amerika (CEDLA), 1987 - 2000; 682; 1 omslag
        - Interuniversitaire onderzoeksschool CERES, 1993 - 2004; 683; 1 omslag
        - Samenwerkingsverband IO-Instituten-LUW (SAIL), 1994 - 1999; 684; 1 omslag
      - Samenwerkingscontracten buitenlandse universiteiten en andere instellingen, C.1.6.2
        - Europa, 1994 - 2003; 685; 1 omslag
        - Afrika, 1991 - 2008; 686; 1 omslag
        - Noord- en Zuid Amerika, 1987, 1991 - 2007; 687; 1 omslag
        - Azië, 1990 - 2009; 688; 1 pak
        - Oceanië, Fiji, 1994 - 1996; 689; 1 omslag
    - Studenten, promovendi en alumni, C.1.7
      - Album Studiosorum, 1952-2009; 772-774; 3 delen
        - Volume I 1952 jul-1966 mei, 772
        - Volume II 1965 aug-1980 feb, 773
        - Volume III 1980 aug-2009 feb, 774
      - "Welcome to the Institute of Social Studies", 1976, 1979, 1986, [1994]; 690; 1 omslag
      - ISS Participants, 1972-1973 - 1976-1977; 691; 1 omslag
      - ISS Programme participants, 1977-1978 - 1978-1979; 692; 1 omslag
      - ISS Master’s participants, 1977-1978 - 1991-1992; 693; 1 pak
      - ISS Diploma participants, 1979-2001; 694-695; 2 omslagen
        - 1979 - 1980 - 1990 - 1991, 694
        - 1991 - 1992 - 2001, 695
      - Master’s Participants and Diploma programme in Population & Development, 1992-1995; 696; 1 omslag
      - Special Graduate Programme in Economic Planning Participants, july-december 1992, 697; 1 deel
      - Master of Arts Participants, 1995 - 2009; 698-699; 2 omslagen
        - 1995 - 2001, 698
        - 2001 - 2009, 699
          2004-2005 met bijlage
      - Participants of the 1999 Development Law and Social Justice Programme, 700; 1 deel
      - PhD participants, ca. 1991 - 2001; 701; 1 omslag
      - M.Phil. Participants 1982-1991, ca. 1991; 702; 1 deel
      - Alumni List, 1975 - 1978; 703; 1 omslag
      - Survey ISS Participants 1970-1980 / John Rodrigues, december 1980; 704; 1 stuk
      - ISS alumni surveys 2003-2004, 2006-2007, 2003 - 2007; 705; 1 omslag
      - Alumni policy ISS: 2002-2006 / R.A. Bekius, 2001; 706; 1 omslag
      - Snowball alumni newsletter/journal, 1974 - 1985; 707; 1 omslag
        Fall 1974-Spring 1976, Nr. 9. 1982, Sept 1984-April 1985
      - Alumni magazine, 1990 - 1998; 708; 1 omslag
      - Education, identity and development: interviews with alumni of the institute of social studies the Hague: appendices to the study /Shanti George, 1992; 709; 1 deel
      - ‘Was it worthwhile?’ perceptions of a sample of students graduating from the institute of social studies / by Shanti George, 1998; 710; 1 omslag
        First draft
      - Experiential leadership: reflections of Scholas president Ali Salman, 2001; 711; 1 katern
      - Stukken betreffende Scholas, 1971, 1996, 2003; 712; 1 omslag
      - Magazines of Scholas (Scholas Journal, ISSues, The Loudspeaker), 1979, 1986 - 1988, 1996 - 1999, 2001 - 2004; 713; 1 omslag
        Scholas is de studentenvereniging van de ISS. Incompleet.
      - Stukken betreffende inkomenssituatie PhD studenten, 1993 - 1995; 714; 1 omslag
        Bevat stukken over de PhD staking
      - 50 PhD Theses at the Institute of Social Studies, [ 2004]; 715; 1 katern
      - Jaarboeken studenten, 2003 - 2005; 716; 1 omslag
      - Student counselling, 1985 - 1986; 717; 1 omslag
  - Onderzoek en advies, C.2
    - Algemeen, C.2.1
      - Annual report of the Research Advisory Committee (R.A.C.) for the financial year 1973, 1974; 718; 1 stuk
      - Research Programme. ISS, 1977; 719; 1 stuk
      - Research Programme. It’s implementation. ISS, 1980; 720; 1 stuk
      - Progress reports on Projects, 1995 - 1998; 721; 1 omslag
      - Onderzoek (jaar)rapport / Progress report on Research, 1995 - 1997, 2008; 722; 1 omslag
        1997 met bijlagen
      - Onderzoeksbeleid/Research Policy, 1997, 1998, 2003, 2004; 723; 1 omslag
      - Professors and associate professors at ISS: brief curricula vitae and latest publications (1985-93) / Research office Institute of Social Studies, 1995; 724; 1 omslag
      - Evaluatie Onderzoek, 2003, [2005]; 725; 1 omslag
      - Research Master, 2002 - 2004; 726; 1 omslag
      - ‘Centres’, 1999 - 2007; 727-730; 4 omslagen
        Een ‘Centre’ is stafgroepoverschrijdend en heeft geen formele status. Het orgaan is o.a. bedoeld om nieuwe onderwijs- en onderzoeksactiviteiten te genereren en de zichtbaarheid van het ISS te verhogen.
        - ‘Centres’ binnen het ISS / Centre for the Study of Transition and Development (CESTRAD), 1999 - 2006, 727; 1 omslag
        - Civil Society Building (CSB), 2004, 728; 1 omslag
        - Religie en ontwikkeling, 2005, 729; 1 omslag
        - International Centre for Child and Youth Studies (ICCYS), ca. 2005 - 2007, 730; 1 omslag
  - Office of Research, Projects and Advisory Service (Orpas), C.3
    Orpas ontstond in 1999. Orpas is de opvolger van deels de Research en Project Office en deels van de ISSAS.
    - Projectbeleid en Project and Advisory Services, 1990 - 1999; 731; 1 omslag
    - Info Projecten, ca. 1990 - 1992; 732; 1 band
    - Orpas jaarverslagen, 1999 - 2004; 733-739; 7 omslagen
      - 1999, 733
      - 2000, 734
      - 2001, 735
      - 2002, 736
      - 2003, 737
      - 2004, 738
      - 2005, 739
    - Brochures over onderzoek bij ISS/Orpas, 1999 - 2004, 2008; 740; 1 omslag
    - Policy Framework on Externally Financed Projects / Orpas, 2000; 741; 1 stuk
    - Orpas projecten, 1993 - 2004; 742-745; 6 omslagen
      - Ethiopia, 1993 - 2000, 742
      - Namibia, 1993 - 2003, 743
      - Vietnam, 1996 - 2003, 744
      - Costa Rica, 1996 - 2004, 745
    - Latijns Amerika Alfa project, 1994 - 2001; 746-747; 2 omslagen
      - 1994 - 1996, 746
      - 1999 - 2001, 747
- Gedeponeerde archieven, D.
  - Stichting Bijzondere Leerstoel "Religion, human rights and social change", D.1
    - Stukken betreffende de Stichting (o.a. de oprichting), 1996 - 2001 (2007); 748; 1 omslag
    - Agenda’s, notulen met vergaderstukken, januari 1998 - 4 december 2006; 749; 1 omslag
    - Jaarverslagen, 1999-2006, 2008, [ 2000] - 2009; 750; 1 omslag
    - Stukken betreffende de Inaugurele rede, 2000; 751; 1 omslag
      Beperkt openbaar?
    - Summary reports of research trips, februari 2001 - maart 2002; 752; 1 omslag
    - Ingekomen stukken en afschriften van uitgegane stukken, 1999 - 2006 (2011); 753; 1 omslag
    - Overeenkomsten en werkplannen, 1999, 2005; 754; 1 omslag
    - Stukken betreffende courses and seminars, 1999 - 2002; 755; 1 omslag
  - ISS Advisory Services (ISSAS), D.2
    In 1981 opgericht om de rol van het ISS als adviseur over ontwikkelingsbeleid en planning verder uit te bouwen.
    - Stukken betreffende ISSAS, reglementen, afschrift akte van oprichting, (concept)statuten, 1980 - 2004; 756; 1 omslag
    - ISSAS in the Eighties: A Midpoint Assesment, 1984; 757; 1 omslag
    - Annual Reports, 1985 - 1998; 758; 1 omslag
      Ook enkele drafts
    - Annual Accounts, 1992 - 1999; 759; 1 omslag
    - Progress Reports, 1980 - 1993; 760; 1 omslag
    - Audit Reports, 1995 en 1998; 761; 1 omslag
    - ISS/ISSAS relationship, 1988 - 1997; 762-763; 2 omslagen
      - dec 1988 - sept 1994, 762
      - oktober 1994 - oktober 1997, 763
    - Vergaderstukken van de ISSAS Board, nrs.: 18, 27, 28 en 35-51, (1992 - 1994) december 1995 - oktober 2001; 764; 1 omslag
    - Lijsten van projecten en een lijst met publicaties, 1994, 1997; 765; 1 omslag
    - Brochure: ISSAS professional services for social and economic development and international cooperation, 1992; 766; 1 deel
  - Automobilistenclub, D.3
    - Nuffic-ISS automobilistenclub (N.I.A.C.), 1981; 767; 1 omslag
  - Stichting Studenten Hulpfonds ISS, D.4
    Opgericht op 11-2-1975.
    - Stukken betreffende de Stichting, 1975, 1983, 2003 - 2006; 768; 1 omslag
  - Stichting Studentenhuisvesting, D.5
    Opgericht in 1981. Taken: In eerste instantie eigendom en beheer van pand De Ruyterstraat 63. Optredend als werkgever voor medewerkers van het ISS kinderdagverblijf [tot 1995] en de schoonmakers van het ISS.
    - Stukken betreffende de Stichting, 1975, 1983 - 1996, 2001 - 2004; 769; 1 omslag
  - Stichting Friends of the ISS, D.6
    - Stukken betreffende de Stichting, 2002 - 2004; 770; 1 omslag